In this lesson, we will explore how to set up a privacy policy page.
It is recommended to all website owners to add a privacy policy page to your site,
as it is a document required by law that discloses the information you collect about visitors to your website.
As an example, let's visit WordPress.org and see what their privacy policy page looks like.
This privacy policy describes how WordPress.org uses and protects information that is given to them.
Next, let's discuss how WordPress has made life easier for users.
When we open up Pages, you will have noticed that WordPress has simplified the process
by providing us with a template privacy policy that you can modify to meet your needs.
There are various subheadings with suggested text,
but you can add and remove whatever you need.
And some of the topics that are covered include Media, Cookies,
Embedded content from other websites, Who we share your data with,
How long we retain your data, What rights you have over your data, and lastly, Where we send your data.
When you are happy with your changes, click Publish.
Next, we can focus our attention on privacy settings.
Let's make our way to the dashboard, scroll down to Settings and click on Privacy.
You will be able to edit or preview your privacy policy page
and check out the Privacy Policy Guide for extra help and support.
When you scroll down, you have the option to create a new privacy policy
and change or assign the privacy policy page you are using.
In the last section, I am going to add my privacy policy page to my footer.
So, I am going to make my way to Appearance and then click on Editor.
And this will of course take me into the Site Editor where I can edit my header and footer.
I can of course edit my header and footer within the template.
But to edit my footer with less distractions, I am going to make my way to Navigation
and select the footer navigation.
I will open up the Template Editing Mode and then click on the Inserter of the Navigation block
and add my privacy page.
Once added, I can click Save.
And when I return to my Home Template and scroll down,
I will see that my privacy policy page is now part of my footer below Quick Links.
It is also worth mentioning that you can generate a privacy policy using a plugin.
All the best as you set up your privacy statement.